Guide to the Fales Library Collection of Artwork and Memorabilia MSS.509
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library Collection of Artwork and Memorabilia
1851-2016, undated
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.509
8.5 Linear Feet in 22 items
The Fales Library Collection of Artwork and Memorabilia was created in 2017 to track artworks that had been found in the collection and artworks donated to the Fales Library & Special Collections. The collection consists of artworks found in the collection and artworks donated to the Fales Library & Special Collections. The artworks consist of paintings, drawings, photographs, religious objects, realia, and sculptures. The artworks date from 1851 to 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Scope and Contents
The Fales Library Collection of Artwork and Memorabilia consists of artworks found in the collection and artworks donated to the Fales Library & Special Collections. The artworks consist of paintings, drawings, photographs, religious objects, realia, and sculptures. The artworks date from 1851 to 2016.
Historical Note
The Fales Library Collection of Artwork and Memorabilia was created in 2017 to track artworks that had been found in the collection and artworks donated to the Fales Library & Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Memorabilia.; Works of art.
- Temple Scott, 1941; cuid6032; 1 item one painting (Item MSS.509.cuid6032)
  Scope and Contents
  Artist: Florence Thaw
  Paintings (visual works)
- Large woven rug, Undated; cuid6035; 1 item one rug (Item MSS.509.cuid6035)
  rugs (textiles)
- Portrait of Elmer Bobst, Undated; cuid6041; 1 item one painting (Item MSS.509.cuid6041)
  Artist: D. Bermey
- Sign: The Ridiculous Theatrical Company, 1978-1987; cuid6042; 1 item one sign (Item MSS.509.cuid6042)
  Artist: Christopher Scott
  Information signs.
- Portrait of William Faulkner, 1962; cuid6057; 1 item one photograph (Item MSS.509.cuid6057)
  Artist: Jack Cofield
  Photographs.
- Man Prone Over Open Dishwasher, Undated; cuid6188; 1 item one photograph (Item MSS.509.cuid6188)
  Artist: Jimmy De Sana
  Former owners: Bill Olander, Craig Owens
  Gift of: David Deitcher
- Marvin & Ron, June 10, Undated; cuid6189; 1 item one painting (Item MSS.509.cuid6189)
  Artist: Bob WitzRon Kolm
  Gift of: Ron Kolm
- Dylan Thomas at Bay, March 1950, 1958; cuid8697; 1 item one painting (Item MSS.509.cuid8697)
  Artist: Gene Derwood
- Portrait of Tim Dlugos, 2016; cuid21251; 1 item one painting (Item MSS.509.cuid21251)
  Artist: Philip Monaghan
- Judaica, velvet bag, undated; MSS.509.cuid21312 (Item MSS.509.cuid21312)
- Judaica, candlestick, undated; MSS.509.cuid21313 (Item MSS.509.cuid21313)
- Judaica, candlestick, undated; MSS.509.cuid21314 (Item MSS.509.cuid21314)
- Judaica, hanukkiah, undated; MSS.509.cuid21315 (Item MSS.509.cuid21315)
- photograph of monkey (Amber Creeger, photographer), undated; MSS.509.cuid21316 (Item MSS.509.cuid21316)
- Henry Fernald (Kaiden-Keystone Photos), undated; MSS.509.cuid21317 (Item MSS.509.cuid21317)
- James Joyce, 1966; MSS.509.cuid21373 (Item MSS.509.cuid21373)
- Satyr awakening a nymph, unknown; MSS.509.cuid21374 (Item MSS.509.cuid21374)
- James Joyce Portrait, 1935; MSS.509.cuid21375 (Item MSS.509.cuid21375)
- Ron Kolm, 1988; MSS.509.cuid21376 (Item MSS.509.cuid21376)
- Portrait of Henry P. Barry, undated; MSS.509.cuid21377 (Box 1)
- Portrait of Anna Tracey, undated; MSS.509.cuid21378 (Box 1)
- Portrait of Sir Walter Scott, 1851; MC.509.cuid21459 (Item MC.509.cuid21459)
  Artist: William Smellie Watson
- Bust of Marcello Tomassi, 1996; MSS.509.cuid21914 (Box 2)